<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cross-region on jq1.io</title>
    <link>https://jq1.io/tags/cross-region/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cross-region on jq1.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 15:44:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jq1.io/tags/cross-region/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finally published to the Terraform Cloud public registry</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/finally_published_to_public_registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 15:44:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/finally_published_to_public_registry/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone,
Great news! The modules that power TNT Architecture and Super Router projects for scaling VPCs and TGWs in AWS have been published to the Terraform Cloud public registry at v1.0.0, like FINALLY!
Tiered VPC-NG Centralized Router (includes Generate Routes to Other VPCs) Super Router Intra VPC Security Group Rule Super Intra VPC Security Group Rules The modules are mostly the same as what&amp;rsquo;s in my Terraform development repo at v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slappin&#39; chrome on the WIP</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/slappin_chrome_on_the_wip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 10:49:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/slappin_chrome_on_the_wip/</guid>
      <description>Reflection in the Rear-View: Initially, I thought the TNT Architecture project and Super Router project were &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; to scale VPCs and TGWs in AWS.
But, after looking back on what was built there were so many areas for improvement that I could not resist the extended refinement and discovery.
I went ahead and gave the most useful Terraform networking modules a clean chrome wrapping with encoded engravings.
Most of the work went into internal module changes and consolidating my favorite patterns to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$init super refactor</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/init_super_refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 08:11:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/init_super_refactor/</guid>
      <description>Aaaand we&amp;rsquo;re back with another heavy hitting round of super refactorization in Terraform!
I think the first iteration of Super Router for AWS went well.
It allowed us to peer and route both intra-region and cross-region TGWs and VPCs with a single module.
But there was one really annoying flaw.
The caveat in the design is that the peer TGWs will have to go through the Super Router&amp;rsquo;s local provider region to get to other peer TGWs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Powered, Super Sharp, Super Router!</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/super_router/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 16:07:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/super_router/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s up world?!
Welcome back for moar spicy cloud networking Terraform takes because we servin&amp;rsquo; them HOT over here so let&amp;rsquo;s dig in!
This is a follow up to the generating routes blog post.
TNT Architecture Recap The Terraform Networking Trifecta project demonstrated the ability to &amp;ldquo;scale&amp;rdquo; AWS VPCs in Terraform code by adding VPC objects to a list.
Example VPC architecture but with auto named subnets: With Tiered VPCs we can narrow down the context (ie app, cicd, general) and maximize the use of smaller network sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
