<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>intra-region on jq1.io</title>
    <link>https://jq1.io/tags/intra-region/</link>
    <description>Recent content in intra-region on jq1.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 10:49:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jq1.io/tags/intra-region/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Slappin&#39; chrome on the WIP</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/slappin_chrome_on_the_wip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 10:49:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/slappin_chrome_on_the_wip/</guid>
      <description>Reflection in the Rear-View: Initially, I thought the TNT Architecture project and Super Router project were &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; to scale cross-region VPCs &amp;amp; TGWs in AWS.
But, after looking back on what was built there were so many areas for improvement that I could not resist the extended refinement and discovery.
I went ahead and gave the most useful Terraform AWS networking modules a clean chrome wrapping with encoded engravings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$init super refactor</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/init_super_refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 08:11:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/init_super_refactor/</guid>
      <description>Aaaand we&amp;rsquo;re back with another heavy hitting round of super refactorization in Terraform!
I think the first iteration of Super Router for AWS went well.
It allowed us to peer and route both intra-region and cross-region TGWs and VPCs with a single module.
But there was one really annoying flaw.
The caveat in the design is that the peer TGWs will have to go through the Super Router&amp;rsquo;s local provider region to get to other peer TGWs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Powered, Super Sharp, Super Router!</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/super_router/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 16:07:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/super_router/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s up world?!
Welcome back for moar spicy cloud networking Terraform takes because we servin&amp;rsquo; them HOT over here so let&amp;rsquo;s dig in!
This is a follow up to the generating routes blog post.
TNT Architecture Recap The Terraform Networking Trifecta project demonstrated the ability to &amp;ldquo;scale&amp;rdquo; AWS VPCs in Terraform code by adding VPC objects to a list.
Example VPC architecture but with ephemeral subnets: With Tiered VPCs we can narrow down the context (ie app, cicd, general) and maximize the use of smaller network sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
