<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>decentralized-hub-spoke-topology on jq1.io</title>
    <link>https://jq1.io/tags/decentralized-hub-spoke-topology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in decentralized-hub-spoke-topology on jq1.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 15:44:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jq1.io/tags/decentralized-hub-spoke-topology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finally published to public registry</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/finally_published_to_public_registry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 15:44:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/finally_published_to_public_registry/</guid>
      <description>Hey cloud networkers,
Great news! The modules that power TNT Architecture and Super Router projects have been published to the Terraform Cloud public registry at v1.0.0, like FINALLY!
The modules are mostly the same as what&amp;rsquo;s in my Terraform development repo at v1.4.9.
This is my contribution to the Terraform community.
Ended up moving generate_routes_to_other_vpcs module into Centralized Router because it&amp;rsquo;s actually a function of that router.
And, of course, the TNT Architecture Demo and Super Router Demo have been upgraded, hell yeah!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slappin&#39; chrome on the WIP</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/slappin_chrome_on_the_wip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 10:49:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/slappin_chrome_on_the_wip/</guid>
      <description>Reflection in the Rear-View: Initially, I thought the TNT Architecture project and Super Router project were &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; to scale VPCs and TGWs in AWS.
But, after looking back on what was built there were so many areas for improvement that I could not resist the extended refinement and discovery.
I went ahead and gave the most useful Terraform networking modules a clean chrome wrapping with encoded engravings.
Most of the work went into internal module changes and consolidating my favorite patterns to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$init super refactor</title>
      <link>https://jq1.io/posts/init_super_refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 08:11:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jq1.io/posts/init_super_refactor/</guid>
      <description>Aaaand we&amp;rsquo;re back with another heavy hitting round of super refactorization in Terraform!
I think the first iteration of Super Router for AWS went well.
It allowed us to peer and route both intra-region and cross-region TGWs and VPCs with a single module.
But there was one really annoying flaw.
The caveat in the design is that the peer TGWs will have to go through the Super Router&amp;rsquo;s local provider region to get to other peer TGWs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
